Now commencing the
57th Exterior Scouting Mission!
Move out!
We believe that the basement of
Eren Jaeger's home in Shiganshina
houses a secret of the Titans
that not even he is aware of.
We are to head there.
You rookies will be here,
between the wagon defense
squad and the scout support squad.
Here, you will run alongside
spare horses and relay signals.
Our special operations squad
will be positioned here,
on standby in the
rear of the center rank.
This is the safest position
"Row 5, Center: Standby"
in the formation.
Not even the supply wagons
get this level of treatment.
This isn't an Abnormal...
--Cis!
--It has intelligence!
It's just like the Armored Titan,
the Colossal Titan, and Eren!
It's a human clad in a Titan body!
This one's way more
athletic than the other ones!
Damn! We were...
We were too naïve!
She's protecting her nape?!
Damn! There's no escape now!
Jean! Avenge that suicidal maniac!
She stopped?
It was her! She killed him!
That maniac finally got himself killed,
as part of the right wing!
She killed him!
I'd say we bought enough time!
Now let's get
away from her, quick!
Huh? Oh no...
Why?
Is she heading for Eren?!
I won't let your deaths be meaningless
even if I'm the last one standing
In both hands, Gloria
What sings is Sieg
On my back, Flügel der Freiheit
Clenched determination to my left chest
What slashes across is Linie der Torheit
Soaring across the azure skies
Flügel der Freiheit
"Forest of Giant Trees"
"The 57th Exterior Scouting Mission, Part 2"
How is your ODM gear, Armin?
It's all right. It unclasped properly,
so it doesn't seem to be broken.
I see. That's good to hear.
But now what?
We only have one horse.
If Jean's horse comes back,
all three of us can get moving again, but...
Damn, what's the deal?
Reiner's horse came back;
why won't mine?
And we can't afford
to stay here any longer...
Worst case scenario,
we'll have to leave someone here...
How will we choose
who that someone should be?
Armin, because he's hurt?
Reiner, because he's big
and would be hard to ride with?
Or should I go look
for my horse on foot?
Damn!
It's screwed up that we
even have to consider that!
The three of us just
managed to escape death!
This is one hell of a raw deal!
Armin.
Hey, Armin!
I take it you're
still a bit mixed-up?
Yeah.
I'm still a little dazed...
I see.
Still, we need to decide now.
It's a difficult choice, but it looks
like one of us has to stay behind.
Wait!
Let's fire a smoke signal first.
If the formation
kept moving forward,
Row 4, Squad 3
should be nearby now.
That was an emergency
smoke signal.
I doubt it's enough to
get our point across, though.
Armin. We'll only
wait three minutes.
By then, we need
to choose who'll stay--
I'll stay.
But, in exchange, I need
you to report about something.
Only to Commander Erwin, if possible.
No, wait, Armin.
You can report it yourself.
Someone's coming!
And they've brought two horses!
That's...
Christa!
Guys! Are you okay?!
Huh? Hey, that's my horse!
Whoa, there.
Calm down, Buchwald!
He came racing my way;
something must've really spooked him.
Did you guys fight a Titan?!
Armin!
You're hurt! Are you all right?!
Yes, more or less.
I'm impressed you willingly came
here after seeing that smoke signal.
I happened to be nearby,
plus I'd found Jean's horse.
You have a way with horses, not to
mention a remarkable sense of virtue.
We owe you one.
I'm just glad.
So very glad that the worst
didn't happen to you guys...
She's a god...
A goddess...
I want to marry her...
Well, we better
hurry back into formation!
Oh, yeah! There should
be orders to retreat soon!
Still, turning back not even
an hour after leaving the wall...
Things look way
grimmer than I thought.
Plus, she's headed away from the
lead command squad for some reason.
She?
Green smoke signals?!
It sounds like the plan is to change
course but otherwise continue the operation.
Oh, no! They're not
ordering us to retreat?!
What the hell is
Commander Erwin thinking?!
All soldiers have the authority to
decide if the operation can't continue...
Have the signals not
reached the command squad?!
Whether or not they know, we only
have one option in this situation:
defer to their judgment.
Smoke signals. Green.
Oruo. You fire it.
Understood, Sir!
It feels like we're making
smooth progress right now.
But...
...I wonder how things actually are.
I wonder if people have
already died on the front line...
Reporting, Sir!
It's an oral message!
Right wing spotters decimated!
Detection network partially out!
Please pass this
message on to the left!
You heard him, Petra. Go.
Yes, Sir!
The right wing?!
Isn't that where Armin is?
Still, he and the others
are positioned closer to the center.
The Titans couldn't
have advanced that far in.
Black signals?!
An Abnormal?!
Eren. You fire it.
Y-Yes, Sir!
This is disgraceful.
We've let them get
pretty deep inside the formation.
Just over there is a Titan...
Below that black smoke...
...someone is fighting?
Damn!
Look down here...
...you monster!
Now!
Three spots at once!
She seems pretty smart,
but she can't defend against them all!
Cut her spine, ligaments,
or anywhere else that can stop her!
Attack!
So many are dead 'cause of you!
We're gonna torture you to death!
She jumped?!
L-Let go!
Reporting takes priority!
I have to let
them know about that one!
An Abnormal?!
This far in?!
Let's take it out!
We can't let it get any further in!
The right wing's been wiped out?!
Then why aren't we retreating?!
"Row 3-1, Transport"
I don't know! Commander's orders!
Just pass word on to the left!
What's the deal?
"Row 1-13: Spotting"
We've been going straight east for a while now.
Yes, and our destination
is the old city to the south...
"Row 1-5: Spotting"
At this rate, the formation's going to run right into it!
Yeah.
There it is.
A forest of giant trees!
It looks like Titans
have passed through here.
The path is devoid of vegetation.
Even the wagons
could get through here.
Inform those behind us
that only the center wagon
defense squad is to enter the forest.
Yes, Sir!
Excuse me, Sir...
It looks like the center rank
is taking that forest path.
That means we'll
run smack into the forest.
Then we go around.
Y-Yes, Sir!
Hey, now.
What are we doing at
this sightseeing attraction?!
Now we're really straying
from our original
destination and return point!
I don't know...
I don't know, but this is
what Commander Erwin decided.
He seems to have
some plan in mind, but...
Plan? Are you kidding me?
What, is he gonna throw a welcome
party for us rookies at this tourist spot?
No, I don't think so.
That was a joke.
Either way, we got
that giant broad after us.
Regardless of what plan he has,
we can't afford to stop here.
My guess is we're passing through
here on our way to somewhere else.
All soldiers, halt!
All right! Listen up, rookies!
We're now going to
take up intercept positions!
Unsheathe and wait in the trees!
If any Titans try to enter the forest,
stop them with full force!
Huh?
Umm, Sir? Why would we need to--
Shut up and follow orders!
You gotta be kidding me...
What the hell's happening?!
H-Hey.
It looks like only the
center rank went into the forest.
What does that mean
for the formation?
There is no formation anymore.
The forest is blocking us side squads,
so our only choice is to go around.
We've lost our spotting capabilities.
Why didn't we change course
and avoid the forest altogether?
Did Commander Erwin
misread his map or something?
I don't know.
It's possible we got pushed here trying
to avoid the threat on the right side.
Maybe.
This is insane...
First we abandon our original
plan of establishing a logistics base...
Then, instead of running home with
our tails between our legs like we should,
we go on a daring sightseeing tour...
And, if that wasn't enough,
now we're just supposed to stand here
and keep Titans out of the forest?
Him and his idiotic orders...
He's gonna hear you.
And he doesn't even explain anything.
That's a new one to me.
But I doubt he's all that
calm on the inside either.
What do you mean?
Sometimes leaders get deemed incompetent
by their men in extreme situations
and end up dying from
mysterious stab wounds to the back.
It's not that rare, is all I'm saying.
Jean... What are you thinking of doing?
Relax, will you?
I'm just a little irritated at
this whole situation.
I'm gonna follow orders, of course.
Keeping Titans out of the forest...
You agree that's
what we should do too, right?
You look like you know something.
Uhh...
5-meter Titan approaching!
Why did he bring the platoon here?
Just what is
Commander Erwin thinking?
No, that's not right.
That isn't what I should be asking.
What I should be asking is...
...what if the Female Titan
is pursuing Eren
and the commander is aware of that?
Captain!
Captain Levi!
What?
"What?" This is a forest, Sir!
We have no way of detecting
approaching Titans this far in
with only the center rank!
Something seems to be on our right too.
How are we supposed to avoid
the Titans or protect the wagons now?!
Quit whining about the obvious.
We can't do any
of those things anymore.
B-But why--?!
Take a good look around, Eren.
See all these absurdly huge trees?
This is the perfect environment
for using omni-directional mobility gear.
And use that middling
head of yours to think.
Use your brain for
once if you don't wanna die.
Yes, Sir!
I see...
I'm still new to this; that's why
I don't understand the situation.
And he won't give me a simple answer
because I still need to learn for myself.
I bet that's how these
experts learned to fight, too.
Dammit, what are we doing here?
Seriously...
What the hell's going on?
Huh?!
Don't tell me...?!
Don't tell me no one
knows what's going on?!
Not even Captain Levi?!
If my theory that the Female
Titan is after Eren is correct,
then there's only one
reason why we've come here.
Commander Erwin
intends to confront her here!
Armin.
Our orders are to
"keep Titans out of the forest," right?
In other words...
We don't need to
actually fight them...
...right?
--A black smoke signal?!
--From right behind us!
Must be whatever's on the right!
Draw your swords.
If it shows itself,
we'll only have a moment.
Move!
It's fast!
There's no way to
avoid it inside this forest!
It's catching up!
Captain! Let's switch to ODM!
Captain!
You're not going anywhere!
Reinforcements from the rear!
Captain! Give your orders!
Let's take it out! It's dangerous!
We should take care of it!
I'll cut it to shreds!
Idiot! You walked
right into your own doom!
What you're chasing is
a team of expert Titan-killers!
Captain Levi!
Captain!
--Please give us orders!
--It's about to catch up to us!
Let's take it out here!
That's why we entered
this forest! Isn't it, Captain?!
Captain! Your orders!
Everyone, cover your ears.
If, by chance, I'm not me
then who's to say that you're you?
Can you pick up the pieces of your heart
that fell apart like a broken sand castle?
The voice of someone calling out
changed into ringing in my ears
It's as if time has stopped
Now wake up
I made my way out of the deep darkness
I fled like a swift wind
We used to be like living corpses,
but now we head beyond the walls
Let's meet again
in a place not on any map
The Female Titan makes chase,
leaving a bloodbath behind.
Eren can only flee as he watches
his comrades die before his very eyes.
Amid this, he's forced to make a decision.
"Bite"
"The 57th Exterior Scouting Mission, Part 3"